Mankind Survived... But Not Alive.
Zombie Apocalypse is a action, horror, science
fiction film directed by Nick Lyon.
Months after a zombie plague has wiped out 90 percent of the American population, a small group of
survivors fight their way cross-country to a rumored refuge on the island of Catalina.
Henry, played by Ving Rhames.
Ramona, played by Taryn Manning.
Julian, played by Johnny Pacar.
Cassie, played by Lesley-Ann Brandt.
Mack, played by Gary Weeks.
Kevin, played by Gerald Webb.
Zombie apocalypse is a subgenre of apocalyptic and post-apocalyptic fiction in
which society collapses due to overwhelming swarms of zombies.
Usually, only a few individuals or small bands of
human survivors are left living.
There are many different causes of a zombie apocalypse in fiction.
In some versions, the reason the dead rise and attack humans is unknown; in others, a
parasite or infection is the cause - framing the film like a plague.
Some stories have every corpse zombify regardless of the cause of death, whereas others
require exposure to the infection, most commonly in the form of a bite.
The genre originated in the 1968 American horror film Night of
the Living Dead, which was directed by George A.
Romero, who took inspiration from the 1954 novel
I Am Legend by Richard Matheson.
Romero's film introduced the concept of the flesh-eating zombie and spawned numerous
other fictional works, including films, video games, and literature.
The zombie apocalypse has been used as a metaphor for various contemporary fears, such
as global contagion, the breakdown of society, and the end of the world.
It has repeatedly been referenced in the media and has inspired various fan activities such as
zombie walks, making zombie apocalypse a dominant genre in popular culture.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.